

Katie Gilbert

Marketing Professional

Phone: 971-212-3698 Email: ktagilbert@gmail.com Portfolio: ktagilbert.github.io/katalog/

Profile

I am a creative digital marketer with extensive content writing experience stemming from four years studying journalism and three years of content marketing experience. That, combined with indepth analytical abilities, make me uniquely qualified to drive inbound leads and create solid digital marketing strategies. Success includes a 64% increase in site traffic and 150% improvement in overall social engagement.

Skills

Social Media Marketing

Google Analytics & Google Search Console

Keyword Research

Content Creation and Content Strategy

SEO

HTML, CSS, & Markdown

Education

Seattle University - 2011-2014Bachelor of Arts, Creative Writing

School Projects:

Founder & President of Literary Society

Experience

Brandefined - Chief Content Officer June 2016 - January, 2017

At Brandefined, I hit the ground running. It was my job to manage 70 clients and to improve work efficiency in the content department. To achieve my goals, I implemented new processes and workflows while also writing content for around 50 recurring clients.

- Wrote blog articles, press releases, web content, social media content, and eNewsletters
- Managed a team of writers.
- · Lead sprint meetings and handled scrum duties
- · Performed on-page SEO for new client websites

Velocity Marketing Partners - SEO Specialist

February 2016 - June 2016

Here, I improved campaign reporting for our SEO clients as well as managed all of the SEO client accounts. I also shared my knowledge of SEO, social media marketing, and inbound lead generating across departments.

- · Created industry targeted lead campaigns
- · Created an internal company style guide for online content
- · Managed the team's editorial calendar
- Facebook advertising
- · Wrote informative blog articles about SEO & web development

Adpearance - Inbound Marketing Intern

November 2015 - February 2016

I sought the opportunity to work here so I could gain further fundamental digital marketing knowledge. I worked with their automotive team to help with client facing reports, social media content, and copy-editing.

- · Performed on-page SEO for automotive clients
- · Crafted social media messages for automotive clients
- · Copy-edited landing page content for client websites

Caring Senior Service - Digital Marketing Specialist October 2014 - June 2015

Here, I helped build & execute a digital strategy from the ground up, developed promotional campaigns for new content pieces, and was the social media manager for over 20 franchise locations.

- Increased overall social engagement by over 150%
- · Successfully increased site traffic by 64%
- · Worked directly with franchisees